

Shaikh Tahmidur Full Stack Developer

in www.linkedin.com/in/stahmid

☑ <u>shaikhtahmidurrahman1@gmail.com</u>

**** +973 38012087

Portfolio: https://devtahmid.github.io/portfolio/

Github: https://github.com/devtahmid

About Me

With my passion for development, I can make applications that drive engagement and satisfy clients. As my CV and portfolio indicate, I can make user-friendly interfaces and reliable back-end solutions. I would like to use my skills to uplift organizations and create real world impact.

Skills

- Full stack web application with PHP & ReactJS
- Bootstrap and Tailwind
- C# form application with .Net Core
- Console applications in C++ & Java
- Selenium and automation python scripts
- Ionic Angular cross platform mobile app

Education

B.SC. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Bahrain - 2023

SECONDARY SCHOOL

The Indian School, Bahrain - 2018

SENIOR SECONDARY SCHOOL

The Indian School, Bahrain - 2016

Certifications

- Advanced React Scrimba
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Amazon
- Power BI Data Analyst Associate Microsoft

Work Experience

Freelancing at Upwork (March 2023- May 2023)

Built two projects- Home Car Charger Rental system, and Special Disorders Help App with Member and Admin functions which are both live right now on my portfolio

Internship at Truckly (July 2022-September 2022)

Contributed to the backend using PHP and MySql, where I learnt to use MVC framework and built the (truck) booking and feedback system. Also employed Javascript DOM manipulation and AJAX calls to increase interactivity and improve client user experience

Notable Projects

BlockEstate, Real Estate on the Blockchain Blockchain app created using NextJS, Solidity, and NFT

- Made use of React-Bootstrap with NextJS and create views by fetching data from the IPFS network
- Learnt how to use the different rendering techniques of NextJS such as periodic static generation, server side rendering, and dynamic paths

PetPrism Pet Shop Portal

Web app created using PHP, bootstrap, JS and MySQL

- Learnt how to create dynamic pages using PHP
- Used ajax functions to get live updates without page reload
- Used Javascript DOM manipulation to create interactive forms

Pharmacy Management System

Web app created using PHP, bootstrap, JS and MySQL

- Learnt how to manage different views for different users. eg: customer, pharmacist, admin
- Tested key features and security flaws to make the webapp production ready for real world usage
- Implemented a database for user information, auction items, and media uploads using MySql



Shaikh Tahmidur Rahman Full Stack ReactJS & PHP Developer

Portfolio: https://devtahmid.github.io/portfolio/ Github: https://github.com/devtahmid

About Me

I am a full-stack developer with experience in CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and MySQL, as well as frameworks such as ReactJS, NextJS, and Bootstrap. I am passionate about developing user-friendly interfaces and reliable back-end solutions.

My goal is to use my skills to create great web applications that help people and make a positive impact on their lives. I have a drive to constantly learn and expand my knowledge and I am confident I can bring a lot to any project.

Skills

- Full stack web application with PHP & Bootstrap
- ReactJS and NextJS
- Console applications in C++ & Java
- C# form application with .Net Core
- Selenium and automation python scripts
- Ionic Angular cross platform mobile app

Education

B.SC. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Bahrain (2018-2023)

SECONDARY SCHOOL

The Indian School, Bahrain (2016-2018)

SENIOR SECONDARY SCHOOL - GPA 10/10

The Indian School, Bahrain 2016

Work Experience

Internship at Truckly (July 2022-September 2022)

Contributed to the backend using PHP and MySql, where I learnt to use MVC framework and built the (truck) booking and feedback system. Also employed Javascript DOM manipulation and AJAX calls to increase interactivity and improve client user experience

Notable Projects

BlockEstate, Real Estate on the Blockchain

Blockchain app created using NextJS, Solidity, NFT, and IPFS

- Made use of React-Bootstrap with NextJS and create views by fetching data from the IPFS network
- Learnt how to use the different rendering techniques of NextJS such as periodic static generation, server side rendering, and dynamic paths

PetPrism Pet Shop Portal

Web app created using PHP, bootstrap, JS and MySQL

- Learnt how to create dynamic pages using PHP
- Used ajax functions to get live updates without page reload
- Used Javascript DOM manipulation to create interactive forms

Pharmacy Management System

Web app created using PHP, bootstrap, JS and MySQL

- Learnt how to manage different views for different users. eg: customer, pharmacist, admin
- Tested key features and security flaws to make the webapp production ready for real world usage
- Implemented a database for user information, auction items, and media uploads using MySql

Quizzlet

Quiz app created using ReactJS

- Learnt how to fetch data from API and use them in react
- Learnt how to style react components

Tenzies

Dice game created using ReactJS

- Learnt how to manage interdependent states
- Made use of react-confetti package

Certifications

- Advanced React Scrimba
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Amazon Web Services